Guide to Central Washington University College of Business of Business, Files 1973-2018
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Guide to the Central Washington University College of Business, Files
1973-2018
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archives@cwu.edu
RG-0078
6 linear feet 12 boxes
The collection is mainly documents and memos. There is one box with audio tapes and two display boards. There are twoboxes of portraits.
College of Business, Self-Evaluation and Accreditation Files
The School of Business and Economics was established by the Board of Trustees of CWSC on August 5, 1974. President Brooks, believed the college was a necessary addition to the Central, “whose time had come.” In 2001, the SBE recommended that name be changed to College of Business (COB). In 2008, the COB changed its name to CB.
The collection contains the Self-evaluation, and accreditation reports from the College of Business during the years between 1980-2013. It also contains portraits fo faculty, staff, and administraters from 1973-2018
The collection is split into five series. The first contains self-evaluation reports. The second series contains ephemera and newsletters. The third series is called 3D objects. It contains audio tapes and display boards. The fourth series contains documents about the accreditation process for the CWU College of Business. The fifth series is photographic portraits.
Open to the public for research.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Central Washington University College of Business--Archives
Central Washington University
Ellensburg, Washington
Economics; Banking; Marketing
Colleges and Universities
- School of Business, Self-Evaluation, 1994 (Box-folder Series 1)
- School of Business, Self-Evaluation: Preconditions, 1994 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Self-Evaluation, Precondition Appendices, 1994 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Self Evaluation, Mission, 1994- (Box-folder 1-3)
- Self Evaluation, Mission Appendices, 1994- (Box-folder 1-4)
- Self Evaluation, Faculty, 1994- (Box-folder 1-5)
- Self Evaluation, Faculty Appendices, 1994- (Box-folder 1-6)
- Self Evaluation, Curriculum, 1994- (Box-folder 1-7)
- Self Evaluation, Curriculum Appendices, 1994- (Box-folder 1-8)
- Self Evaluation, Instruction, 1994- (Box-folder 1-9)
- Self Evaluation, Students, 1994- (Box-folder 1-10)
- Self Evaluation, Students Appendices, 1994 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Self Evaluation, Intellectual Contributions, 1994 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Self Evaluation, Intellectual Appendices, 1994 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Self Evaluation, Executive Summary, 1998 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Self Evaluations, Preconditions, 1998 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Self Evaluation, Mission, 1998 (Box-folder 1-16)
- Self Evaluation, Faculty Self Evaluation, 1998- (Box-folder 1-17)
- Self Evaluation, Curriculum, 1998 (Box-folder 1-18)
- Self Evaluation, Instruction, 1998 (Box-folder 1-19)
- Self Evaluation, Students, 1998 (Box-folder 1-20)
- Self Evaluation, Intellectual Contributions, 1998 (Box-folder 1-21)
- Self Evaluation, Accounting, 1998 (Box-folder 1-22)
- Self Evaluation, Economics, 1998- (Box-folder 1-23)
- Self Evaluation, Finance and Law, 1998 (Box-folder 1-24)
- Self Evaluation, Management, 1998 (Box-folder 1-25)
- Self Evaluation, Marketing, 1998 (Box-folder 1-26)
- Self Evaluation, OMIS, 1998 (Box-folder 1-27)
- Mock Peer-Review, Correspondence, Team, 2004 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Self Evaluation Report volume 1, 2005 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Self Evaluation Report volume 2, 2005 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Self Evaluation Report volume 1, 2009 (Box-folder 2-4)
- Self Evaluation Report volume 2, 2009 (Box-folder 2-5)
- AASCB Salary Survey, 2009-2013 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Ephemera, Newsletters, College of business newsletters and ephemera from the years 1991 to 2007. (Box-folder Series 2)
- Newsletters, 1991-2006 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Ephemera, 1999-2007 (Box-folder 4-2)
- 3d objects, Audio tapes and display boards from the College of Business. (Box-folder Series 3)
- Audio Tapes, Display Boards, 1993 (Box-folder 5-1)
- Accreditation Documents, Documents about the accreditation process and procedures for CWU's College of business from 1980 to 2000. (Box-folder Series 4)
- Initial Accreditation, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 6-1)
- Fall Advisor Visits, 1994 (Box-folder 6-2)
- AASCB Accreditation Recommendations, 1994 (Box-folder 6-3)
- Executive Summary, 1994 (Box-folder 6-4)
- John Miller Consultation, 1996 (Box-folder 6-5)
- International Business and OMIS, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 6-6)
- Advisor visits, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 6-7)
- Briefing Book, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 7-1)
- Briefing Book, 1989 (Box-folder 7-2)
- AASCB Self Study Report, 1990 (Box-folder 7-3)
- Briefing Book, 1990 (Box-folder 7-4)
- Accreditation Advisors, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 7-5)
- AASCB Correspondence, 1993-2003 (Box-folder 7-6)
- AASCB Accreditation Structure and Procedures, 2000 (Box-folder 7-7)
- AASCB Policies, 2000 (Box-folder 7-8)
- SBE Retreat, 2000 (Box-folder 7-9)
- AASCB Annual Report, 2001 (Box-folder 7-10)
- Faculty Demand Survey, 1985-2001 (Box-folder 7-11)
- AASCB Faculty Demographics, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 7-12)
- AACSB Member Survey, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 7-13)
- Business School Fact Form, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 7-14)
- School of Business, Timeline, 2009 (Box-folder 7-15)
- School of Business and Econmics Historical Perspective, 1999- (Box-folder 8-1)
- Executive Meeting Notes, 2003- (Box-folder 8-2)
- Executive Meeting Notes, 2004- (Box-folder 8-3)
- Vote Revision to "Standards of Faculty Research, 2005- (Box-folder 8-4)
- Accreditation, Workflow, 2005-2007 (Box-folder 8-5)
- Executive Committee Minutes, 2006- (Box-folder 8-6)
- Executive Meeting Minutes Jan-May, 2007- (Box-folder 8-7)
- Execeutive Meeting Minutes Jun-Dec, 2007- (Box-folder 8-8)
- Executive Meeting Minutes Jan-May, 2008- (Box-folder 8-9)
- Execeutive Meeting Minutes Jun-Dec, 2008- (Box-folder 9-1)
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes Jan-Sep, 2009- (Box-folder 9-2)
- Executive Meeting Minutes Sep-Dec, 2009- (Box-folder 9-3)
- Executive Board Committee Minutes, 2010- (Box-folder 9-4)
- College of Business Executive Committee, 2011-2012 (Box-folder 9-5)
- College of Business Executive Committee, Meeting Materials, 2011-2012 (Box-folder 9-6)
- Program and Budget Priorities, Quality Indicators, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 10-1)
- Growth History of the School of Business, Louise, Danton, 1993 (Box-folder 10-2)
- Campaign for Accreditation, Newspaper Clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 10-3)
- How It All Began, Business Week At Central, 1974-1994 (Box-folder 10-4)
- Policies and Procedured of the CWSC Advisory Council of Economic Business Administration (Box-folder 10-6)
- School of Business and Economics, Board of Visitors, 1974-1984 (Box-folder 10-8)
- Portraits, 1973-2018; Photographic portraits of faculty, staff, and administrators of the College of Business at Central Washington University. (Box-folder Series 5)
- Melissa Becker, 2006-2018; Emeritus Lecturer of Accounting (Box-folder 11-1)
- Ronald Tidd, 2001-2018; Emeritus Professor of Accounting (Box-folder 11-2)
- Debbie Boddy, 2001-2016; Distinguished Servant College of Business (Box-folder 11-3)
- Jay D. Forsyth, 1996-1998; Interim Dean, School of Business and Economics (Box-folder 11-4)
- Gerald L. Cleveland, 1987-1992; Dean, School of Business and Economics (Box-folder 11-5)
- Lyle E. Ball, 1974-1980; Dean, School of Business and Economics (Box-folder 11-6)
- Allen K. Gulezian, 1973-2000; Emeritus Professor of Business Administration (Box-folder 11-7)
- Leslie C. Mueller, 1974-2000; Emeritus Professor of Business Administration (Box-folder 11-8)
- Laura Wilson, 1982-2000; Distinguished Civil Servant, School of Business and Economics (Box-folder 11-9)
- Lawerence A. Danton, 1980-1987; Dean, School of Business and Economics (Box-folder 11-10)
- Joan F.Mosebar, 1992-1993; Acting Dean, School of Business and Economics (Box-folder 11-11)
- David P. Dauwalder, 1993-1996; Dean, School of Business and Economics (Box-folder 11-12)
- Hugh M. Spall, 1975-2006; Emeritus Professor of Management (Box-folder 11-13)
- Jay Forsyth, 1969-2007; Emeritus Professor of Accounting (Box-folder 11-14)
- Richard Mack, 1972-2008; Emeritus Professor of Economics (Box-folder 11-15)
- Don Nixon, 1986-2011; Emeritus Professor of Management (Box-folder 11-16)
- Gary Heesacker, 1972-2011; Emeritus Professor of Accounting (Box-folder 11-17)
- James Nimnicht, 1988-2012; Emeritus Professor of Management (Box-folder 11-18)
- Sharon Damm, 1994-2012; Distinguished Civil Servant (Box-folder 11-19)
- Eldon Johnson, 1977-2014; Emeritus Professor of Finance and Supply Chain Management (Box-folder 11-20)
- Norman Gierlasinski, 1986-2014; Emeritus Professor of Accounting (Box-folder 11-21)
- Kathryn Martell, 2012-; Dean, College of Business (Box-folder 11-22)
- Roy Savoian, 1998-2012; Dean, College of Business (Box-folder 11-23)
- Roy Savoian, 1998-2015; Emeritus Professor of Economics (Box-folder 11-24)
- Karen Martinis, 1979-2015; Emeritus Professor of Accounting (Box-folder 12-1)
- F. Lynn Richmond, 1994-2014; Emeritus Professor of Management (Box-folder 12-2)
- Edward Golden, 1977-2001; Emeritus Professor of Business Administration (Box-folder 12-3)
- George W. Brooker, 1990-2001; Emeritus Professor of Business Administration (Box-folder 12-4)
- Donald J. Cocheba, 1970-2002; Emeritus Professor of Economics (Box-folder 12-5)
- John O. Moore, 1980-2002; Emeritus Professor of Accounting (Box-folder 12-6)
- Barbara K. Rodden, 1975-2002; Distinguished Civil Servant, Business Administration (Box-folder 12-7)
- Stanley Jacobs, 1983-2005; Emeritus Professor of Administration (Box-folder 12-8)
- Wayne A. Fairburn, 1972-2005; Emeritus Professor of Administration (Box-folder 12-9)
- Allen C. Vautier, 1975-2006; Emeritus Professor of Accounting (Box-folder 12-10)
- Alva E. Tradewell, 1937-1971; Emeritus Professor of Business Administration (Box-folder 12-11)
- Harold S. Williams, 1948-1977; Emeritus Professor of Business Administration (Box-folder 12-12)
- Patrick R. O'Shaughnessy, 1964-1999; Emeritus Professor of Accounting (Box-folder 12-13)
- W. Clair Lillard, 1968-1987; Emeritus Professor of Economics (Box-folder 12-14)
- Wolfgang W. Franz, 1969-1998; Emeritus Professor of Economics (Box-folder 12-15)
- Edward S. Esbeck, 1978-1999; Emeritus Professor of Business Administration (Box-folder 12-16)
- C. Boyd Johnson, 1982-1994; Emeritus Professor of Business Administration (Box-folder 12-17)